ixigo.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy – About ixigo

## **ixigo Privacy Policy**

###  **Last updated: 24th May 2018**

This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of Le Travenues Technology Private Limited (“ixigo”) on the collection, use and disclosure of your information when you use the ixigo Service, via the ixigo website, your mobile phone, or through one of ixigo’s applications for mobile devices (including but not limited to iOS/Android applications). We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our [Terms of Service](https://www.ixigo.com/html/info/terms_of_use.ixi).

The terms “we”, “us”, and “our website” refer to www.ixigo.com and the terms “you” and “your” refer to you, as a user of ixigo.com. The term “personal information” means information that you provide to us which personally identifies you to be contacted or identified, such as your name, phone number, email address, and any other data that is tied to such information.

###  **Information Collection and Use**

ixigo uses information we collect to analyze how the Service is used, diagnose service or technical problems, maintain security, personalize content, remember information to help you efficiently access your account, monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns, and track User Content and users as necessary to comply with the Copyright and Information Act, Information Technology Act 2000, and other applicable laws of India.

###  **User-Provided Information**

You provide us information about yourself, such as your name, e-mail address, mobile number etc. if you register for a member account with the Service. Your name and other information you choose to add to your profile will be available for public viewing on the Service. We may use your email or phone to send you Service-related notices (including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail). We may also use your contact information to send you marketing emails, push notification, SMS or IVR call. If you do not want to receive such communication, you may opt out by following the instructions in the message or informing us over an email. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses.

If you use your Facebook, Twitter, or other social networking site (“SNS”) account information to sign in to ixigo, we will collect and store your SNS user ID, and other information that you explicitly allow us to access when using an SNS login.

You also provide us information in User Content you post to the Service. Your questions, answers, and other contributions on the Service, and metadata about them (such as when you posted them), are publicly viewable on the Service, along with your name (unless the Service permits you to post anonymously). This information may be searched by search engines and be re published elsewhere on the Web in accordance with our [Terms of Service](https://www.quora.com/about/tos).

When you use a debit or credit card or other payment method to your ixigo account, a third party that handles payments for us will receive your card information. To keep your financial data secure, we do not store card information on our servers.

If you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to the Service, we will ask you for that person’s email address and automatically send an email invitation. You may also use our contact importer tool to help you upload your friends’ email addresses so you can find friends who are already on ixigo or invite friends to the Service. ixigo stores this information to send invitations, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted, to track the success of our invitation service, and to identify your friends on ixigo.

 **PERMISSIONS REQUIRED FOR USING OUR MOBILE APPLICATIONS**

When the ixigo app is installed on your phone or tablet, a list of permissions appears and are needed for the app to function effectively. There is no option to customize the list. The permissions that ixigo requires and the data that shall be accessed and its use is as below:

 **Android permissions:**

 **Device & App history:** We need your device permission to get information about your device, like OS (operating system) name, OS version, mobile network, hardware model, unique device identifier, preferred language, etc. Basis these inputs, we intend to optimize your travel booking experience, use OS specific capabilities to drive great in-funnel experiences using components of device’s OS, etc.

 **Identity:** This permission enables us to know about details of your account(s) on your mobile device. We use this info to auto-fill your email ID’s and provide a typing free in-funnel experience. It helps us map email ID’s to a particular user to give you the benefit of exclusive travel offers, wallet cash-backs, etc. It also allows facilitating your Facebook and Google+ login.

 **Location:** This permission enables us to give you the benefit of location specific deals and provide you a personalized in-funnel experience. When you launch ixigo app to make a travel booking, we auto-detect your location so that your nearest airport or city is auto-filled. We also require this permission to recommend you nearest hotels in case you are running late and want to make a quick last minute booking for the nearest hotel. Your options are personalized basis your locations. For international travel, this enables us to determine your time zone and provide information accordingly

 **Phone:** The app requires access to make phone calls so that you can make phone calls to hotels, airlines and our customer contact centers directly through the app.

 **Contacts:** If you allow us to access your contacts, it enables us to provide a lot of social features to you such as sharing your hotel/ flight/ holidays with your friends, inviting your friends to try our app, send across referral links to your friends, etc. We will also use this information to make recommendations for hotels where your friends have stayed. This information will be stored on our servers and synced from your phone.

 **Photo/ Media/ Files:** The libraries in the app use these permissions to allow map data to be saved to your phone’s external storage, like SD cards. By saving map data locally, your phone doesn’t need to re-download the same map data every time you use the app. This provides you a seamless Map based Hotel selection experience, even on low bandwidth network.

 **Wi-Fi connection information:** When you allow us the permission to detect your Wi-Fi connection, we optimize your experience such as more detailing on maps, better image loading, more hotel/ flights/ package options to choose from, etc.

 **Device ID & Call information:** This permission is used to detect your Android ID through which we can uniquely identify users. It also lets us know your contact details using which we pre-populate specific fields to ensure a seamless booking experience.

 **Calendar:** This permission enables us to put your travel plan on your calendar.

 **IOS Permissions:**

 **Notifications:** If you opt in for notifications, it enables us to send across exclusive deals, promotional offers, travel related updates, etc. on your device. If you do not opt for this, updates for your travel like PNR status, booking confirmation, refund (in case of cancellation), etc. will be sent through SMS.

 **Contacts:** If you opt in for contacts permission, it enables us to provide a lot of social features to you such as sharing your hotel/ flight/ holidays with your friends, inviting your friends to try our app, send across referral links to your friends, etc. We will also use this information to make recommendations for hotels where your friends have stayed. This information will be stored on our servers and synced from your phone.

 **Location:** This permission enables us to give you the benefit of location specific deals and provide you a personalized in-funnel experience. When you launch our app to make a travel booking, we auto-detect your location so that your nearest Airport or City is auto-filled. We require this permission to recommend your nearest hotels in case you are running late and want to make a quick last minute booking for the nearest hotel. Your options are personalized basis your locations. For international travel, this enables us to determine your time zone and provide information accordingly.

###  **Information Collected Automatically**

When you use the Service, we use persistent and session cookies and other tracking technologies to: (a) store your username, password and authentication tokens; (b) analyze the usage of the Service; (c) customize the Service to your preferences; and (d) control the advertising displayed by the Service. A persistent cookie remains on your computer after you close your browser so that it can be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Service. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

We may also use other Internet technologies, log files, clear GIFs, Flash technologies, and other similar technologies, to deliver or communicate with cookies and track your use of the Service. We also may include clear GIFs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to determine whether the message has been opened. As we adopt additional technology, we may also gather additional information through other methods.

We use these automated technologies to collect and analyze certain types of information we consider to be non-personal information, including: (a) information related to the devices you use to access or interact with the Service, such as: IP addresses, geolocation information, unique device identifiers and other information about your mobile phone or other mobile device(s), browser types, browser language; and (b) information related to the ways in which you interact with the Service, such as: referring and exit pages and URLs, platform type, the number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time you used the Service, and other similar information. We may also capture other data, such as search criteria and results.

ixigo discloses a subset of this automatically collected information publicly. Specifically, you consent to ixigo’s disclosure of information related to the ways in which you interact with the Service, such as: landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages (including questions and answers viewed), the date and time you used the Service, and other similar information on the Service to other ixigo users, along with your name and profile picture. If you do not wish to have this information disclosed to the public, you may opt out of this feature.

We may collect different types of information about your location, including general information (e.g., IP address, zip code) and more specific information (e.g., GPS-based functionality on mobile devices used to access the Service), and may use that information to customize the Service with location-based information and features. If you access the Service through a mobile device and you do not want your device to provide us with location-tracking information, you can disable the GPS or other location-tracking functions on your device, provided your device allows you to do this.

ixigo may allow third parties to serve advertisements on the Service and on third-party services and use other third parties to help us collect and analyze information about your use of the service, generate aggregate site usage statistics and provide content sharing services to support the Service. These third parties may also use cookies and similar technologies to collect similar non-personal information about your use of the Service. ixigo does not control the third parties’ use of such technologies and their use is governed by those parties’ privacy policies.

###  **How We Share Your Information**

Personally Identifiable Information: ixigo may share your personally identifiable information with third parties for the purpose of providing the Service to you or with third parties offering combined services with ixigo. If we do this, such third parties’ use of your information will be bound by this Privacy Policy. We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of ixigo (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.

We may share or disclose your information with your consent, such as if you choose to sign on to the Service through a third-party service. We cannot control third parties’ use of your information.

ixigo may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or summon or if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect ixigo’s rights or property.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information: We may aggregate and/or anonymize information collected through the Service so that the information does not identify you. We may use aggregated, anonymized, and other non-personally identifiable information for any purpose, including for research and marketing purposes, and our use and disclosure of such information is not subject to any restrictions under this Privacy Policy.

ixigo may allow third-party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Service and on third-party services. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on ixigo. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content. ixigo does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. However, please note that if an advertiser asks ixigo to show an advertisement to a certain audience and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. The ixigo Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third-party advertisers. Please consult the respective privacy policies of such advertisers for more information.

###  **How We Protect Your Information**

ixigo uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to ixigo or guarantee that your information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

All payments on the Website are secured. This means all Personal Information you provide is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us.

Website has stringent security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Whenever you change or access your account information, we offer the use of a secure server. Once your information is in our possession we adhere to strict security guidelines, protecting it against unauthorized access.

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, ixigo will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

###  **Your Choices About Your Information**

You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through the Service, in which case ixigo may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update or correct your account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account. You can always unsubscribe from our commercial or promotional emails, SMS, notifications but we will still send you transactional and relational emails about your account use of ixigo.

###  **Your Rights Available to Help You Manage Your Privacy**

You may have certain legal rights regarding your personal information depending upon the country you are in or how we interact with you. Subject to the terms of this Privacy Statement we guarantee that you have following key rights wherever you are:  
1) To access your personal information. We will tell you what personal information we hold about you and can provide you with a copy of this; 2) To seek rectification of that personal information. Where the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate we will rectify this, upon your request. Note that this right may be limited in terms of the scope of detail that we will or can rectify; 3) To lodge a complaint to us. We will receive and handle your complaints in accordance with best practice and depending upon where you are and whether we are subject to it, any applicable law. 4) If you wish to access any of these rights, we may ask you for additional information to confirm your identity and for security purposes, in particular before disclosing personal information to you. We reserve the right to refuse to provide this additional information if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. 

We may not always be able to address your request fully, for example if it would impact the duty of confidentiality we owe to others, or if we are legally entitled to deal with the request in a different way.

###  **Links to Other Web Sites**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies.

###  **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on this page to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

If you have any questions about our practices or this privacy policy, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), or send mail to:

Le Travenues Technology Pvt. Ltd.

2nd floor, Veritas Building,

Behind Ibis Hotel, Sector 53,

Golf Course Road,

Gurgaon- 122002
